<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: fail | Vagmi's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/categories/fail/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://vagmim.in/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-30T16:11:28+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://vagmim.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vagmi Mudumbai]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Track Call Taxi - Epic Fail]]></title>
    <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/2010/08/31/first-track-call-taxi-epic-fail/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-31T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vagmim.in/blog/2010/08/31/first-track-call-taxi-epic-fail</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I have got royally screwed by the First Track Call Taxi company. I cannot imagine a more irresponsible call taxi service. I was supposed to be picked up at 4 AM by a driver by the name "Nethaji" but was however informed by the driver upon my calling him at 4:10 AM that the vehicle broke down and he is not picking me up. I called the "office" to only find out that they had trusted that the driver had called me several times while I can vouch that I was awake from 3 AM packing awaiting the phone call from the driver. This level of incompetence is simply staggering. But this is the age of buyer beware. Just because an entry has a "JustDial Guarantee" it does not mean that you are guaranteed a service, let alone good service. It is just guaranteed to be available as a search result. It is quite clear that I will not be using the services of this firm henceforth. Do not deal with these guys. They are simply not worth your time.<br /><br />@JustDial - Please remove the guarantee from their entry and publish this as such. I am not sure if they are masquerading as a call taxi firm and are doing something else. Please note that I am not complaining about the quality of the service. I just did not receive any service at all. In that sense, the JustDial Guarantee does not mean anything to me. Also, let me give you a free SEO tip. Please generate a different URL for each item.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
