<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Vagmi's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://vagmim.in/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://vagmim.in/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-30T16:11:28+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://vagmim.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vagmi Mudumbai]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting started with clojure]]></title>
    <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/2012/12/10/getting-started-with-clojure/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-10T17:18:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vagmim.in/blog/2012/12/10/getting-started-with-clojure</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been playing around with <a href="http://clojure.org/">clojure</a> for a bit now and I can postively say that I am absolutely floored. I have always favored dynamic and more expressive languages. I have a rather unfortunate situation of working with a Java codebase. I like the JVM and the <a href="http://docs.oracle.com/javase/6/docs/technotes/tools/share/jvisualvm.html">tools</a> around it but not the language itself. I have always been fond of lisp. Ever since I read <a href="http://www.catb.org/esr/faqs/hacker-howto.html">&#8220;How to be a hacker&#8221;</a> by Eric Raymond, I wanted to learn both lisp and python. Picking up python was easy. It took my barely a week until I could write a web app in python. With Ruby and Rails the transition was even smoother. My forays into the Lisp world were not that fruitful. I learned both Common Lisp and PLT Scheme. I found that I liked Scheme better than CL. In fact the only lisp I found myself using regularly was elisp. For anything useful in the sense of hacking, I found I was using python a lot. Was lisp then merely an academic language? I had read John McCarthy&#8217;s <a href="http://www-formal.stanford.edu/jmc/recursive.pdf">initial paper</a> and was awed by its simplicity. In the meanwhile I had devoured books and articles on lisp its macros and was even able to appreciate the flamewars about <a href="http://www.cs.indiana.edu/~dyb/pubs/tr356.pdf">hygenic macros</a> and <a href="http://www.cs.oswego.edu/~blue/xex/black/courses/f06/ai1/ECOOP.pdf">CLOS</a>. However, I could not do serious stuff with lisp. I found lisp very had to smuggle in to enterprises. Python and Ruby were far easier to be sold.</p>

<p>Then I met clojure. From its first sight, I knew it was beautiful. It implemented both the CLOS parts with defmulti and hygenic macros from the scheme land. It had nice set of special forms to provide just enough syntactic sugar to be expressive without breaking the language too much. But what is more fascinating about Clojure is that it gets concurrency right. It uses persistent and <a href="http://clojure.org/state">immutable data structures</a> that can be shared across callers. It provides a sane implementation of <a href="http://clojure.org/refs">STM</a> and ties it in beautifully concepts like futures and promises. Its Java interop makes interacting with Java libraries amazingly laconic with macros like the expression threading macro and the dot macros. Bottlenecks that you may have in your code due to the dynamic nature can be easily optimized away using type hinting. And in the Java land there is a library for literally everything. It may not have a nice DSL but thats where clojure comes in.</p>

<p>Ousterhout had formulated a dichotomy between powerful statically typed languages or system programming languages and the expressive dynamically typed languages. With clojure that distinction does not exist or is very nearly invisible. Clojure almost always errs on the side of better performance. At this point, I happen to be working with quite a large dataset that needs to be kept in memory and uses complicated graph traversals using Neo4j. Clojure handles this without breaking a sweat. Similar code written in plain Java would be quite complicated and I was not able to get nearly enough performance with JRuby despite several tricks.</p>

<p>In short, what is your excuse for not using clojure?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Track Call Taxi - Epic Fail]]></title>
    <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/2010/08/31/first-track-call-taxi-epic-fail/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-31T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vagmim.in/blog/2010/08/31/first-track-call-taxi-epic-fail</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I have got royally screwed by the First Track Call Taxi company. I cannot imagine a more irresponsible call taxi service. I was supposed to be picked up at 4 AM by a driver by the name &#8220;Nethaji&#8221; but was however informed by the driver upon my calling him at 4:10 AM that the vehicle broke down and he is not picking me up. I called the &#8220;office&#8221; to only find out that they had trusted that the driver had called me several times while I can vouch that I was awake from 3 AM packing awaiting the phone call from the driver. This level of incompetence is simply staggering. But this is the age of buyer beware. Just because an entry has a &#8220;JustDial Guarantee&#8221; it does not mean that you are guaranteed a service, let alone good service. It is just guaranteed to be available as a search result. It is quite clear that I will not be using the services of this firm henceforth. Do not deal with these guys. They are simply not worth your time.<br /><br />@JustDial - Please remove the guarantee from their entry and publish this as such. I am not sure if they are masquerading as a call taxi firm and are doing something else. Please note that I am not complaining about the quality of the service. I just did not receive any service at all. In that sense, the JustDial Guarantee does not mean anything to me. Also, let me give you a free SEO tip. Please generate a different URL for each item.</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yes Men Fix the World]]></title>
    <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/2010/07/27/yes-men-fix-world/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-27T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vagmim.in/blog/2010/07/27/yes-men-fix-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
This is by far the best movie/documentary I&#8217;ve ever seen. Yes Men deserves a special mention and should be viewed by everyone. This sort of a film can never be published by a corporation steeped in the free market system. The YesMen have made an excellent decision to publish it via thepiratebay.org. The documentary is a very hilarious take on some of the very serious issues that is haunting the world today. A few people in the system have gotten unimaginable money and clout over the affairs of the state. Globalization has made our systems so complicated that no one individual can actually figure it out. Yet it seems that America is making decisions for the rest of the world. A nation where bills and laws are marketed by lobbyists who have deep pockets. This is a perfect recipe for a disaster.<br /><br />This movie portrays some of the evils of capitalism (that I often find very hard to articulate) in a very simple and effective manner. This movie is a wake up call for us. I guess this is the day of <a href="http://www.timesnow.tv/articleshow/4350441.cms">tapes and sting operations</a>. However, in a country like India where one&#8217;s civil rights are under question, there is no guarantee for one&#8217;s electronic rights. But I firmly believe that an open medium such as the internet is essential if we still have to retain the freedom of speech. <br /><br />You can download the movie from the <a href="http://vodo.net/yesmen">YesMen website</a>. Do not forget to make your donation. I made mine.<br /><br /><object width="640" height="385"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/QnQX09DZLYE&amp;hl=en_US&amp;fs=1"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/QnQX09DZLYE&amp;hl=en_US&amp;fs=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="640" height="385"></embed></object></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The magic of Y]]></title>
    <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/2010/02/19/magic-of-y/"/>
    <updated>2010-02-19T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vagmim.in/blog/2010/02/19/magic-of-y</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I have always been a fan of lisp. I spent my fair deal of time with emacs and emacs lisp. Scheme and Dr.Scheme have always fascinated me. I am searching for a good excuse to put Clojure into action. However, I am sometimes blinded by the awesomeness of Ruby which I do a lot as a part of my day job. But Lisp is too beautiful for my mind to ignore. One of those things that interest a lisp hacker is this concept of fixed point combinator.<br /><br /><blockquote><br />A <b>fixed point combinator</b> (or <b>fixed-point operator</b>) is a <a href="http://vagmim.in/wiki/Higher-order_function" title="Higher-order function">higher-order function</a> that computes a <a href="http://vagmim.in/wiki/Fixed_point_(mathematics)" title="Fixed point (mathematics)">fixed point</a> of other functions. A <i>fixed point</i> of a function <b>f</b> is a value <i>x</i> such that <b>f</b>(<i>x</i>) = <i>x</i>. For example, 0 and 1 are fixed points of the function <b>f</b>(<i>x</i>) = x<sup>2</sup>, because 0<sup>2</sup> = 0 and 1<sup>2</sup> = 1. Whereas a fixed-point of a first-order function (a function on &#8220;simple&#8221; values such as integers) is a first-order value, a fixed point of a higher-order function <b>f</b> is <i>another function</i> <b>p</b> such that <b>f</b>(<b>p</b>) = <b>p</b>. A fixed point combinator, then, is a function <b>g</b> which produces such a fixed point <b>p</b> for any function <b>f</b>:<br /><dl><br /><dd><b>p</b> = <b>g</b>(<b>f</b>), <b>f</b>(<b>p</b>) = <b>p</b></dd><br /></dl><br />or, alternately:<br /><dl><br /><dd><b>f</b>(<b>g</b>(<b>f</b>)) = <b>g</b>(<b>f</b>).</dd><br /></dl><br />Shamelessly ripped from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fixed_point_combinator">Wikipedia</a><br /></blockquote><br /><br />One of the best papers I had read so far is the <a href="http://www.dreamsongs.com/NewFiles/WhyOfY.pdf">Why of Y(pdf)</a>. This derives the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fixed_point_combinator">Y combinator</a> and I thought it was beautiful derivation. However, the author uses terms like currying which is interpreted by my indian mind as a tasty gravy rather than a technique to break down a series of arguments to multiple function calls. But then I read Peter Krumin&#8217;s <a href="http://www.catonmat.net/blog/derivation-of-ycombinator/">derivation of Y combinator</a>. This is just magical. He takes small baby steps with working scheme code and does not mix up terms used in indian recipes. This is by far the best derivation of Y-combinator I read in years.<br /><br /><a href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/loom/2008/02/17/y-combinator/" target="_blank"><br /><img src="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/loom/files/2008/07/y-combinator.jpg" alt="Y combinator" title="Y combinator"/><br /></a><br /><br /><b>Disclaimer:</b> I haven&#8217;t read <a href="http://mitpress.mit.edu/catalog/item/default.asp?ttype=2&tid=4825">The Little Schemer</a> yet. I am now looking for a good excuse to use scheme/clojure for my next project.</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Statistics is important]]></title>
    <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/2010/02/12/statistics-is-important/"/>
    <updated>2010-02-12T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vagmim.in/blog/2010/02/12/statistics-is-important</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
This is important.<br /><br /><a href="http://www.google.co.in/search?q=population+of+india&ie=utf-8&oe=utf-8&aq=t&rls=com.ubuntu:en-US:official&client=firefox-a"><br />The population of india</a> - 1.148 Billion<br /><a href="http://www.google.co.in/search?q=indian+population+growth+rate&ie=utf-8&oe=utf-8&aq=t&rls=com.ubuntu:en-US:official&client=firefox-a">The population growth rate</a> - 1.58%<br />Number of people that will be added this year - 1.8 Million<br /><a href="http://www.google.co.in/search?q=population+of+chennai&ie=utf-8&oe=utf-8&aq=t&rls=com.ubuntu:en-US:official&client=firefox-a">Population of chennai</a> - 4.34 Mio<br /><br />So we will add almost half of chennai in the next year. In this rate, the number of years it will take for us to double our population is approximately 45 years. Think about it. Do you really want to have children? We do not have enough resources to feed the entire country at this point.</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Logarithm to any base in ruby]]></title>
    <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/2010/01/25/logarithm-to-any-base-in-ruby/"/>
    <updated>2010-01-25T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vagmim.in/blog/2010/01/25/logarithm-to-any-base-in-ruby</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Ruby&#8217;s Math module includes functions for a natural log (log to the base e) and the common log (log to the base 10). If you have to have a log to an arbitrary base, you have to write your own. Doing so is trivial.<br /><br /><script src="http://gist.github.com/285744.js?file=log_base.rb"></script><br /><br />I will probably explain the theory behind this another day.</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Markov Chains]]></title>
    <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/12/23/markov-chains/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/12/23/markov-chains</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
You know developers have an itch to implement something cool that they learned about. No can say it better than XKCD.<br /><br /><a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://xkcd.com/208/"><img style="cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 600px; height: 607px;" src="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/regular_expressions.png" border="0" alt="" /></a><br /><br />I learnt about <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markov_chain">Markov Chains</a> today. <br /><br /><blockquote>In mathematics, a Markov chain, named after Andrey Markov, is a discrete random process with the Markov property. A discrete random process means a system which can be in various states, and which changes randomly in discrete steps. It can be helpful to think of the system as evolving once a minute, although strictly speaking the &#8220;step&#8221; may have nothing to do with time. The Markov property states that the probability distribution for the system at the next step (and in fact at all future steps) only depends on the current state of the system, and not additionally on the state of the system at previous steps. Since the system changes randomly, it is generally impossible to predict the exact state of the system in the future. However, the statistical properties of the system at a great many steps in the future can often be described. In many applications it is these statistical properties that are important. - From the wikipedia entry on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markov_chain">Markov Chains</a></blockquote><br /><br />It was so cool that I decided to do something with it. So I wrote a simple helper that generates articles for the app that I was testing. Here is the code in all its glory. It is not the fastest piece of code and is a memory hog, but who cares? <br /><br /><script src="http://gist.github.com/262529.js?file=markov.rb"></script><br /><br />This is how you use it.<br /><br /><script src="http://gist.github.com/262529.js?file=usage.rb"></script><br /><br />And this produced this <a href="http://gist.github.com/raw/262529/f53ad246a37eed108c98f05e6f3327355dff7df5/article.txt">fine article</a>. Isn&#8217;t this cool?</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The problem with certifications]]></title>
    <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/12/08/problem-with-certifications/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-08T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/12/08/problem-with-certifications</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
There was a <a href="http://article.gmane.org/gmane.org.user-groups.linux.ilugc/57656">question</a> on ILUGC today to which I <a href="http://article.gmane.org/gmane.org.user-groups.linux.ilugc/57660">responded</a>. I am reposting it as a blog entry.<br /><br />You should first understand how certifications work from the perspective of a vendor who offers such certification say Microsoft, Redhat or SAP. The vendor has an economic interest in selling his product to a company. The company which buys a product (or a service in case the of Redhat) wants to know if the product/service they buy can be used by people they are going to employ. This is where the brilliance of marketing sets in. <br /><br />They con the students and the candidates in the job market that there are several jobs awaiting them if only they clear the certification in their technology. They then go and talk to all the colleges and institutes like NIIT and convince them to market the certification and give them the necessary materials to make it a course. They then contact book authors who fill in pages and pages with mind numbing facts about the technology. The institute in the meanwhile has started tailoring a course and claims that it can get you from a dud to a certified professional in 3 months. As with any statistical distribution in a country with a billion people, a sizable few take up the certifications. The first few batches are always tough. Only the good guys clear the first 3 or 4 batches. But good guys like to share knowledge. So they share the dumps with the world. <br /><br />The vendor does nothing to oppose this as they need that pool of skills in the market. After they have got enough number of people with the piece of paper with the name of the vendor and a printed signature of the CEO/founder of the company, the marketing department gets busy making powerpoint slides. The slides have graph of stating the number of people who have finished the certification and how easy it would be for their customers to find the right skills. And since the numbers (supply) are aplenty and the licensed customers are a few (demand), by the laws of economics, they should have no problem in finding people with the right skills (and a cheap pay). <br /><br />The mindless HR then goes and &#8220;recruits&#8221; people with certifications. So if you notice, if you are a good candidate, you can lower your value just by getting certified. There are alternative means to improve your employability. You can start contributing to open source for a start. Do not pick difficult projects. If you cannot find a project, try building something. Try creating a simple webapp or a game. I am seeing too many freshers with &#8220;Biometric AI-Driven Neural Network Enabled Grid Based Path Finding World Domination Engine&#8221; on their resumes. And they want me to believe that they did it in 3 months without being able to write fizz buzz in their favorite language. <br /><br />As an employer myself, I would recommend you to do the following. Take up a small project. A small pong game or a simple webapp that solves your problem and document all your learnings in a blog. This will make you a better writer and a better programmer. Use open source technologies. Apart from being the best choice in terms of freedoms that you get, you also get to interact directly with better programmers in mailing lists like these. <br /><br />To pioneer a change, I, on behalf of <a href="http://www.artha42.com">Artha42</a>, am ready mentor a select group of students every year. Your work will be entirely open sourced. I promise that you will not write a single line of proprietary code. That said, we are not Google. We are a small startup with limited resources. We cannot hold something as large as the Google Summer of Code. But we can do something smaller. If you are interested in such an internship opportunity, do drop in a line to careers <at> artha42 <dot> com with &#8220;internship&#8221; in the subject line or visit our <a href="http://www.artha42.com/career.html">careers</a> page.</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[IE is being mean to me again]]></title>
    <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/11/26/ie-is-being-mean-to-me-again/"/>
    <updated>2009-11-26T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/11/26/ie-is-being-mean-to-me-again</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Exactly my sentiments.<br /><br /><object width="560" height="340"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/vTTzwJsHpU8&hl=en_US&fs=1&"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/vTTzwJsHpU8&hl=en_US&fs=1&" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="560" height="340"></embed></object><br /><br />BTW, <a href="http://www.artha42.com">Artha42</a> is also hiring talented and passionate developers. Drop in a like to careers <at> artha42 dot com, if you are interested.</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Artha42 is hiring]]></title>
    <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/11/11/artha42-is-hiring/"/>
    <updated>2009-11-11T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/11/11/artha42-is-hiring</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<a href="http://www.artha42.com">Artha42</a> is hiring. I have been conducting a lot of interviews lately and am completely dissappointed at the state of freshers coming out of engineering colleges. They spend 4 years supposedly studying IT and Computer Science and cannot answer a simple question like <a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/archives/000781.html">fizzbuzz</a>. Come on. I completely agree with <a href="http://krishashok.wordpress.com/">krishashok</a> on this one. Chennai does have concentration camps and they are the bane for a creative society.<br /><br /><object width="560" height="340"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/jpDQ66r1f9M&hl=en&fs=1&"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/jpDQ66r1f9M&hl=en&fs=1&" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="560" height="340"></embed></object><br /><br />If there are guys wanting to work in a fun, passionate and challenging environment, please send your profile to careers <at> artha42.com.</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Modifying Radiant's Database Mailer]]></title>
    <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/10/07/modifying-radiants-database-mailer/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-07T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/10/07/modifying-radiants-database-mailer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Radiant&#8217;s <a href="http://github.com/Aissac/radiant-database-mailer-extension/">Database Mailer</a> is an wonderful extension that can quickly set up mailer forms and add stuff to the database too. But they have tried to do some serious magic to ensure that arbitrary structures can be imported by defining them in the config/environment.rb. That is a bit too hacky for Rails to handle. <br /><br />If you decide to change the structure any time later, you cannot migrate those changes. That is quite a bummer. The crazy part is you cannot uninstall Database Mailer after that either. It keeps reporting an &#8220;undefined method set_schema_version&#8221; error. To uninstall it you have to manually nuke the form_datas (isn&#8217;t data already plural?) table and related attachment tables. You also have to remove the migrations in the schema_migrations table manually. Can someone suggest a better alternative?</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting to tolerate Radiant]]></title>
    <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/09/26/getting-to-tolerate-radiant/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-26T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/09/26/getting-to-tolerate-radiant</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I have been working with <a href="http://radiantcms.org">Radiant</a> for the past couple of days. It is definitely impressive. But I simply hated the fact that you need to work within the confines of the browser&#8217;s textarea to fill in content. This is just plain lame. I am so used to <a href="http://www.vim.org/">Vim</a> that typing within that small window is just plain irritating. You can of course copy paste stuff from and to vim but that is equally lame. Luckily there are a couple of ways you can work around this. <br /><br />The first being the &#8221;<a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/4125">Its all Text</a>&#8221; extension. Its all text enables me to type anything that I type in a text area in vim. It is actually pretty cool.<br /><br />The second being <a href="http://github.com/nelstrom/radiant-file-system-extension">radiant-file-system-extension</a>. It allows me to use the file system and version content with git. Happy hacking with radiant.</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git Branch on the command prompt]]></title>
    <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/04/29/git-branch-on-command-prompt/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-29T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/04/29/git-branch-on-command-prompt</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
It is sometimes very useful to know the git branch you are working on right from the command prompt. You can do this by editing the ~/.bashrc file.<br /><br /><script src="http://gist.github.com/103674.js"></script><br /><br />This will show up a prompt which looks like this and fails gracefully when you are not on a git repo.<br /><br /><pre><code><br />vagmi@deepthought:~/work/testproj[master]$ git checkout new_feature<br />Switched to branch "new_feature"<br />vagmi@deepthought:~/work/testproj[new_feature]$ cd ..<br />vagmi@deepthought:~/work$<br /></code></pre><br /><br />This saves a lot of &#8220;git branch&#8221; when you are coding.</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Liquid and Sinatra]]></title>
    <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/04/22/liquid-and-sinatra/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-22T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/04/22/liquid-and-sinatra</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<a href="http://www.liquidmarkup.org/">Liquid</a> is a templating language used when you need safety for your templates. I was planning to build a CMS and Liquid fit the needs of a templating library really well. I also like <a href="http://www.sinatrarb.com">Sinatra</a> for its simplicity. Unfortunately, Sinatra did not have support for liquid yet so I went ahead and built one. You can get that from my <a href="http://github.com/vagmi/sinatra/tree/liquid">liquid topic branch</a> on github.<br /><br />There are few significant changes that you need to care about when using liquid instead of ERB or HAML. <br /><br /><ul><br /><li>None of the local members or class members declared will be available in your template</li><br /><li>The locals hash is respected even for the layout.</li><br /><li>You have to use  in your layouts, instead of yielding.</li><br /></ul><br /><br />And finally a &#8220;hello world&#8221; sinatra app with liquid.<br /><br /><script src="http://gist.github.com/99714.js"></script><br /><br />Do let me know if you like it.</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Star wars a cappella video]]></title>
    <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/04/15/star-wars-cappella-video/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-15T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/04/15/star-wars-cappella-video</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I just have two words for this. Bloody Brilliant.<br /><br /><embed src="http://www.metacafe.com/fplayer/1969675/star_wars_an_a_capella_tribute_to_john_williams.swf" width="400" height="345" wmode="transparent" allowFullScreen="true" pluginspage="http://www.macromedia.com/go/getflashplayer" type="application/x-shockwave-flash"> </embed></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lets build something already]]></title>
    <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/04/01/lets-build-something-already/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/04/01/lets-build-something-already</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Have ever had the feeling that when you wanted to get started with something, something else had to be done first. If you are a lone hacker banging out code, you are probably fine as you know what you are building. You do not ever have to write it down. But in teams it is vitally important that everyone knows what they are actually building.<br /><br />This is where product managers and project managers come in. They are supposed to have a holistic view of where the project is and where it is heading to. They are the communication hubs who deal with all sorts of information about a project and protect the team as virtual filters. The team then gets information from a single source. But you might ask what happens when there are multiple project managers and product owners but no developers in a planning meeting. The meetings tend to be something like this.<br /><br /><object width="425" height="344"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/YawagQ6lLrA&hl=en&fs=1"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/YawagQ6lLrA&hl=en&fs=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="425" height="344"></embed></object> <br /><br />Fortunately, there is an easy way to deal with this. Get building something already. It is far easier to figure out if the presented solution fits your needs than to speculate on how it would look like. So to all the teams that are suffering from this <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Analysis_paralysis">analysis paralysis</a>, this is my advice. Stop discussing and <a href="http://www.joelonsoftware.com/articles/fog0000000339.html"> start building</a>.</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An interview with Ayn Rand]]></title>
    <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/02/11/interview-with-ayn-rand/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-11T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/02/11/interview-with-ayn-rand</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Objectivism is very relevant, especially in today&#8217;s context.<br /><br /><h2>Part 1</h2><br /><br /><object width="425" height="344"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/7ukJiBZ8_4k&hl=en&fs=1"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/7ukJiBZ8_4k&hl=en&fs=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="425" height="344"></embed></object><br /><br /><h2>Part 2</h2><br /><br /><object width="425" height="344"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/pMTDaVpBPR0&hl=en&fs=1"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/pMTDaVpBPR0&hl=en&fs=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="425" height="344"></embed></object><br /><br /><h2>Part 3</h2><br /><br /><object width="425" height="344"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/zEruXzQZhNI&hl=en&fs=1"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/zEruXzQZhNI&hl=en&fs=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="425" height="344"></embed></object></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A video on the monetary system]]></title>
    <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/02/01/video-on-monetary-system/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/02/01/video-on-monetary-system</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Apart from the conspiracy theory part in the end, this is by far the best explanation of the current monetary system.<br /><br /><embed id="VideoPlayback" src="http://video.google.com/googleplayer.swf?docid=-9050474362583451279&hl=en&fs=true" style="width:400px;height:326px" allowFullScreen="true" allowScriptAccess="always" type="application/x-shockwave-flash"> </embed></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[India, say hello to Corporate Greed]]></title>
    <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/01/07/india-say-hello-to-corporate-greed/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-07T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/01/07/india-say-hello-to-corporate-greed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I was browsing the net about the Satyam fiasco when I saw <a href="http://deadpresident.blogspot.com/2009/01/satyam-mail-to-employees.html">this</a>. What infuriated me were the comments on the blog. They are asking people to stick to the company. This is the time the talented people should extend their middle finger and say <span style="font-weight:bold;">FUCK YOU</span>  to the management. Make sure you enunciate that properly. It works best if told in groups. Tell it with enough intensity to make them die in shame.<br /><br />Stay with Satyam&#8230; Are you crazy?? Jump the ship now. Don&#8217;t commit a career suicide. If the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ramalinga_Raju">man</a> had an ounce of dignity he would not have jeopardized the life of so many people. Indians do not have social security. If a guy in India does not have a job, he is literally on the streets. <br /><br />Ramalinga Raju was sure as hell not maintaining family accounts. The CFO, other senior managment and the financial/controlling staff would have known this. I am sure <a href="http://www.pwc.com/">PWC</a> would have spotted this and would have been duly silenced. Corporate Greed has entered India. <br /><br />If you are a good programmer, you would not have joined Satyam in the first place. But if you are there, jump now. You may not get a raise, but what the hell. You can get out of the depressing situation and have a chance a save your soul.<br /><br />The following days to come in an organization like Satyam would be extremely depressing and would be enough to demotivate a motivated soul. It would be full of bureaucracy where mediocrity will reign supreme. Sounds like a fun place to work?? Hell no. If you you are a rockstar coder, this is your chance. <br /><br />Get out of the hell hole now.</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An accidental trip to erode]]></title>
    <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/2008/12/24/accidental-trip-to-erode/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-24T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vagmim.in/blog/2008/12/24/accidental-trip-to-erode</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I am blogging from <a href="http://www.hotellejardinindia.com/">Hotel Le Jardin</a>. This hotel is amazing and has free Wi-Fi. The breakfast was one of the best I had. How I got here is a topic of another blog post. It was a completely unplanned travel. More on this later. If you are anywhere around this area, Hotel Le Jardin is definitely the place to stay. <br /><br /><iframe width="425" height="350" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=erode,+india&amp;sll=37.0625,-95.677068&amp;sspn=33.572881,79.101563&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=11.185222,77.657804&amp;spn=0.020281,0.038624&amp;z=14&amp;output=embed&amp;s=AARTsJoBWzSyCgVN_Ss2Qly0-GyJT6a3qw"></iframe><br /><small><a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=erode,+india&amp;sll=37.0625,-95.677068&amp;sspn=33.572881,79.101563&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=11.185222,77.657804&amp;spn=0.020281,0.038624&amp;z=14&amp;source=embed" style="color:#0000FF;text-align:left">View Larger Map</a></small><br /><br />Free WiFi Rocks. :-)</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
