<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: frustration | Vagmi's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/categories/frustration/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://vagmim.in/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-01T08:28:26+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://vagmim.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vagmi Mudumbai]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting f&#ked by OO write]]></title>
    <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/2007/06/22/getting-f-by-oo-write/"/>
    <updated>2007-06-22T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vagmim.in/blog/2007/06/22/getting-f-by-oo-write</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Excuse my french. I am really irritated with Open Office and at the point of bashing my laptop screen in frustration. Here I am working my ass off on a business case at 1.45 AM and Ivor brings a PPT that he just found on the net which had some relevant information. My OpenOffice write crashed along with OO Present. I accidently said 'no' to document recovery (it was 1.45 am) and all my overnight work has gone down the drain. I have just downloaded Abiword. I need to get up early and work on it again. <sigh/> The good part is I am getting back to Bangalore tomorrow night. Cant wait to get back home. Can somebody write a decent word processor for Linux. This whole open office thing is a stupid farce. I already use Gnumeric for my excel related activities. I have very basic expectations from a word processor. I guess Abiword should suffice. I am sure it would be a lot faster than OO write. <br /><br />Do you guys know a PowerPoint equivalent on Linux? I don't want to use stupid flaky open office and nor do I want to run Wine. If you guys have any other suggestions it would be great. BTW, Google! When are you building the offline stuff into your docs and spreadsheets. Are you going to have a presentation software?</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
