<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: review | Vagmi's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/categories/review/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://vagmim.in/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-30T15:45:30+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://vagmim.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vagmi Mudumbai]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yes Men Fix the World]]></title>
    <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/2010/07/27/yes-men-fix-world/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-27T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vagmim.in/blog/2010/07/27/yes-men-fix-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
This is by far the best movie/documentary I've ever seen. Yes Men deserves a special mention and should be viewed by everyone. This sort of a film can never be published by a corporation steeped in the free market system. The YesMen have made an excellent decision to publish it via thepiratebay.org. The documentary is a very hilarious take on some of the very serious issues that is haunting the world today. A few people in the system have gotten unimaginable money and clout over the affairs of the state. Globalization has made our systems so complicated that no one individual can actually figure it out. Yet it seems that America is making decisions for the rest of the world. A nation where bills and laws are marketed by lobbyists who have deep pockets. This is a perfect recipe for a disaster.<br /><br />This movie portrays some of the evils of capitalism (that I often find very hard to articulate) in a very simple and effective manner. This movie is a wake up call for us. I guess this is the day of <a href="http://www.timesnow.tv/articleshow/4350441.cms">tapes and sting operations</a>. However, in a country like India where one's civil rights are under question, there is no guarantee for one's electronic rights. But I firmly believe that an open medium such as the internet is essential if we still have to retain the freedom of speech. <br /><br />You can download the movie from the <a href="http://vodo.net/yesmen">YesMen website</a>. Do not forget to make your donation. I made mine.<br /><br /><object width="640" height="385"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/QnQX09DZLYE&amp;hl=en_US&amp;fs=1"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/QnQX09DZLYE&amp;hl=en_US&amp;fs=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="640" height="385"></embed></object></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
