<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: satyam corporate greed | Vagmi's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/categories/satyam-corporate-greed/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://vagmim.in/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-31T22:27:22+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://vagmim.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vagmi Mudumbai]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[India, say hello to Corporate Greed]]></title>
    <link href="http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/01/07/india-say-hello-to-corporate-greed/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-07T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vagmim.in/blog/2009/01/07/india-say-hello-to-corporate-greed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I was browsing the net about the Satyam fiasco when I saw <a href="http://deadpresident.blogspot.com/2009/01/satyam-mail-to-employees.html">this</a>. What infuriated me were the comments on the blog. They are asking people to stick to the company. This is the time the talented people should extend their middle finger and say <span style="font-weight:bold;">FUCK YOU</span>  to the management. Make sure you enunciate that properly. It works best if told in groups. Tell it with enough intensity to make them die in shame.<br /><br />Stay with Satyam... Are you crazy?? Jump the ship now. Don't commit a career suicide. If the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ramalinga_Raju">man</a> had an ounce of dignity he would not have jeopardized the life of so many people. Indians do not have social security. If a guy in India does not have a job, he is literally on the streets. <br /><br />Ramalinga Raju was sure as hell not maintaining family accounts. The CFO, other senior managment and the financial/controlling staff would have known this. I am sure <a href="http://www.pwc.com/">PWC</a> would have spotted this and would have been duly silenced. Corporate Greed has entered India. <br /><br />If you are a good programmer, you would not have joined Satyam in the first place. But if you are there, jump now. You may not get a raise, but what the hell. You can get out of the depressing situation and have a chance a save your soul.<br /><br />The following days to come in an organization like Satyam would be extremely depressing and would be enough to demotivate a motivated soul. It would be full of bureaucracy where mediocrity will reign supreme. Sounds like a fun place to work?? Hell no. If you you are a rockstar coder, this is your chance. <br /><br />Get out of the hell hole now.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
